

# Maho Sasaki

### Contact

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maho-sasaki/

Github: https://github.com/mahos/

Email: Mobile

#### Summary

A frontend developer, with a background in music therapy, trained at Rice University's UX/UI bootcamp. Proficient with HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Angular, Vue, and Node.js. As a frontend developer in a small startup, successfully designed UI and developed both static and dynamic websites catered for scientists at various research laboratories. Strengths lie in the coexisting empathetic user oriented communication skills garnered through years of working and teaching as a music therapist, and problem solving skills as a developer to translate the design idea into real products clients are using daily. I take pride in shipping out user interfaces that clients can rely on for their daily routine.

### Skills

#### **Technical Skillset**

Proficient: Javascript, HTML5, CSS, Angular, Vue, Express/Node.js, Bootstrap3 & 4, PlotlyJS, Amazon S3 Functional: Flask, python, React, Amazon DynamoDB, Illustrator, Photoshop, Final Cut Pro Comfortable with: Docker, git, Amazon elastic beanstalk, EC2, google analytics

#### **Soft Skillset**

Persistence, non-verbal communication/observation skill, adaptability, flexibility, self-motivated learner, resilience and grit.

### Motivators

#### Knowing that there are people out there, that are using the tool I made, or engaged in an activity I designed. I find this quite empowering.

Working hard in small teams.

Innate fear of staying in comfort-zone for too long.

Acquiring new skills and leveling up with age.

Seeing both personal and team growth positively correlate with the amount of effort I put in.

#### **Projects**

#### **DataJoint NEURO**

- International Brain Laboratory Data Portal
  - Explain
- Mesoscale Activity Data Navigator
- Explain DataJoint Documentation Page
- Explain
- DataJoint GUI open source Explain
- DataJoint Playground login / user-setting Explain
- **UI/UX Bootcamp**
- Music Therapy Center of Houston Website Redesign
- Explain, list links to case study, prototype FCC Government Agency Website Redesign
- Explain, list links to case study, prototype Trail Mix: Mobile App Challenge
- Explain, list links to case study, prototype
- Hidgem: Travel App Explain, list links to case study, prototype

### Personal

- Friend's and family's webpage design Explain, list some links
- Abstract book collection page Explain

#### Others List GitHub link

### Work Experience

# Vathes LLC / DataJoint NEURO (February 2017 - Current)

Frontend Developer / Design

- Responsible for designing, developing and maintaining company's websites as well as in developing and maintaining the framework for DataJoint documentation build system.
- Work closely with the data scientists in the team to develop interactive interface for visualizing computation results from the data pipelines, using leading visualization libraries such as PlotlyJS, • Responsible for user interface design, frontend development, maintenance of data visualization custom web application. These web GUI are to be used internally by multi-lab collaboration research projects.

#### Sam Houston State University (September 2016 - May 2018) Instructor & Practicum Supervisor

- Prepared and taught the following courses: Instrumental Skills I, Music Therapy Techniques III Medical, Fundamentals of Guitar, Introduction to Music Therapy, Psychology of Music
- Supervised music therapy practicum students at the following sites: Local preschools, hospice, acute psychiatric unit, outpatient rehabilitation at a local hospital, and local nursing homes.

#### In Home Music Teachers (September 2011 – November 2017) Contract Piano Teacher

• Provides individual piano lessons to young and mature students residing in the Houston area.

# Contract Music Therapist

Southwestern Music Therapy Services (March 2014 – November 2017)

• Responsible for providing weekly individual music therapy sessions for children and adolescents with developmental disorders and emotional and behavioral disturbances.

#### The Harrison Center for Music Therapy (January 1, 2013 – February 2014) Full-time Music Therapist

- Responsible for providing weekly individual music therapy session for young adults with Autism. • Provided weekly group session for the Houston Area Parkinson's Society members.
- Led semi-weekly group music & language groups for Houston Aphasia Recovery Center members. • Provided semi-weekly group sessions for elementary school children with autism at Next Step
- Academy. • Responsible for weekly group session at Viridian Center for Early Childhood interventions.
- Company website development and maintenance.

#### Music Therapy Center of Houston (August 2012 - December 31, 2012) Contract Music Therapist

• Responsible for weekly and semi-weekly music therapy sessions with clients with aphasia, Parkinson's disease, and autism, both in individual and group settings.

# Ballet Class Accompanist (Washington University in St. Louis: Fall/Spring 2009 and 2010)

# • Responsible providing improvised and prepared piano accompaniment for intermediate and advanced

### ballet classes. Provided relaxation music as well as exercise music matching the motion of the dancers.

# Education

#### Washington University in St. Louis • B.A. in Music (September 2004 - May 2008)

UX/UI Bootcamp (June 2020 - Current)

 M.M. in Keyboard Performance(September 2008 - May 2010) **Sam Houston State University** 

# • M.M. in Music Therapy (Equivalency Program: September 2010 - August 2015)

**Rice University** 

#### Training & Certification

- Music Therapist Board Certification (July 2012 Certification #: 10365 Expiration date: 12/31/2022)
- UX/UI Bootcamp Certificate of Completion (Scheduled: December 2020)

Neurologic Music Therapist (NMT) Certification (October 2012)